<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>3.0.10</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpenessManager/releases/download/v3.0.10/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_3.0.10.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpenessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-04-07</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### AI Chat — Providers &amp; Authentication
- **Sign In via OAuth** — All major AI providers now supported via OAuth login in addition to API keys. Choose per agent: use your subscription, no more API keys required for these flows. One click &quot;Sign in with X&quot;, tokens stored securely in Windows Credential Manager, automatic refresh, switch back to API key anytime.
- **Full Enterprise Provider Coverage** — Added Mistral, Azure OpenAI, Google Vertex AI, and AWS Bedrock as first-class providers alongside the existing Anthropic/OpenAI/Google/Ollama/LMStudio/OpenRouter/GitHub Copilot options. Choose EU-based Mistral for GDPR workloads, Azure OpenAI with your own deployment name for compliance-bound data residency, Vertex in europe-west regions with GCP credentials, or Bedrock (Claude/Llama/Mistral/Titan/Nova) with AWS IAM.
- **Prompt Caching** — Significant token cost reduction via stable system prompt architecture. Anthropic achieves 98–99% cache hit rate from the second request onward (~60% cost savings per session). OpenAI/Copilot benefit from automatic caching via stable prefix ordering.

### AI Chat — Multi-Session &amp; Agents
- **Multi-Session Support** — Run multiple AI chat sessions simultaneously. A new Agent Sidebar (toggle with sidebar button) shows all active and completed sessions with live status, elapsed timers, and unread badges. Sub-agents appear indented under their parent session. Create new sessions anytime — even while the AI is working.
- **Per-Session Agent &amp; Provider** — Each session can use a different agent and provider independently. Switch agents mid-workflow without affecting other running sessions.
- **Session Isolation** — Creating a new session during active AI generation no longer interferes with the running session. The old session continues generating in the background while the new session is immediately usable.
- **Cross-Session Auto-Resume** — Sessions automatically resume where they left off when reopened.
- **Inter-Agent Communication** — Sub-agents can send messages to each other and to the main agent bidirectionally, enabling collaborative multi-agent workflows.
- **Named Sub-Agents** — Sub-agents now have display names for easier identification in the Agent Sidebar and session history.
- **Fork Sub-Agent with Worktree Isolation** — Sub-agents can work in isolated git worktrees (separate branches), preventing file conflicts when multiple agents edit code simultaneously.
- **Sub-Agent Permission Inheritance** — Sub-agents inherit tool permissions from the parent agent and can bubble new grants back up.

### AI Chat — UX &amp; Input
- **Unified Skills &amp; Slash Commands** — Skills and slash commands are now a single system. Type `/` to see all available commands and skills in a combined popup with Tab autocomplete. Clicking a skill in the palette or typing `/skill-name` invokes it the same way — the command name appears in accent color, while the AI receives the full skill instructions behind the scenes. The AI discovers available skills automatically and can invoke them proactively when a task matches. Supports both flat `.md` files and `SKILL.md` directory format.
- **@-Mention File Picker** — Type `@` to open a directory-navigation file picker. Browse folders, click to attach files directly as context for the AI.
- **Command Queue** — Send messages while the AI is still working. Messages are queued with priority (now/next/later) and processed automatically after the current response completes. No more waiting for the AI to finish before typing the next instruction.
- **Voice Dictation** — Speak to the AI using Whisper speech recognition (local model or API). Choose push-to-talk or toggle mode. Configure language, model, and hotkey in Settings → Dictation.
- **Skill Template Engine** — Skills now support `{{variables}}` and `{{#if}}` conditionals for dynamic prompt templates that adapt to context.
- **Channel Notifications** — External systems (OPC UA subscriptions, MCP server notifications) push real-time events into active AI chat sessions. The AI can react to PLC alarms, value changes, and MCP events automatically — e.g., an OPC UA overtemperature alarm triggers AI diagnosis.

### AI Chat — Context &amp; Memory
- **Agent Memory** — The AI remembers facts, preferences, and project context across sessions. Memory is stored locally and searchable.
- **Per-Agent Memory Scope** — Memory can be scoped to local (this session), project, or user level. Different agents can have independent memory spaces.
- **Context Window Guard** — A 4-tier visual warning system shows context usage with color-coded indicators: normal (gray), warning at 80% (yellow), error at 90% (red), auto-compact at 93%. The AI automatically compacts context before hitting the limit.
- **Tool Loop Detection** — The AI automatically detects repetitive tool-call patterns (generic repeat, ping-pong, no-progress) and breaks out of infinite loops with a circuit-breaker mechanism.
- **Compaction Improvements** — Context compaction now preserves more relevant information and updates summaries incrementally instead of replacing them.
- **Tool Output Guard** — Large tool outputs (e.g., huge git logs or file reads) are automatically truncated to prevent context overflow from a single oversized response.

### AI Chat — Agent Configuration
- **Model Failover Chain** — Configure fallback models per agent in Settings → Agents. If the primary model fails (rate-limit, server error), the AI automatically tries the next fallback model. Supports cross-provider failover (e.g. Anthropic → OpenAI).
- **Auth Rotation** — Add multiple API keys per agent in Settings → Agents. Keys are rotated automatically via round-robin; rate-limited keys receive a cooldown period. Increases effective rate limits without manual intervention.
- **Per-Agent MCP Servers** — Each agent can have its own dedicated MCP server connections defined inline or by reference, enabling specialized tool sets per agent.
- **Per-Agent Hooks** — Define event-driven automation rules per agent (e.g., auto-format after file edits, validation before commits). Supports event, pattern, and decision hooks.
- **Deferred Tool Loading** — Tools are loaded on demand. Sub-agents only receive the tools they actually need, reducing token usage and improving response quality.

### AI Chat — SCL &amp; Code
- **SCL Expert** — Enhanced SCL code generation with Siemens Programming Styleguide compliance, integrated code review, and direct editor integration for AI-generated code.
- **AWL→SCL Converter** — New agent and skill for AI-assisted migration of STL (AWL) code to SCL. Drop AWL source files into the chat for automatic conversion.
- **NF003 Block Headers** — AI-generated SCL code now includes standardized NF003-compliant block headers with title, version, author, and description fields.

### Git Integration
- **Colored Status Badges** — File change indicators in the Working Copy and Commit Detail views are now displayed as colored, rounded badges (Modified, Added, Deleted, Renamed, etc.) instead of plain text labels.
- **Shared &quot;Deal with Local Changes&quot; Control** — Checkout Branch, Checkout &amp; Fast-Forward, and Create Branch dialogs now use a consistent shared control for selecting how to handle local changes (Keep, Stash &amp; Reapply, Discard), replacing duplicated radio button groups.
- **LFS File Operations in Context Menus** — Right-clicking a file in the Working Copy now shows LFS Track (by filename or extension) and LFS Lock/Unlock options when LFS is enabled. For repositories with multiple remotes, Lock/Unlock shows a submenu per remote.
- **Issue Tracker Links** — Commit messages now show clickable links for issue references (e.g. `#123`, `PROJ-456`). Configure patterns and URL templates per repository via Repository Settings → Issue Tracker tab. Supports multiple tracker rules simultaneously.
- **Clickable URLs in Commit Messages** — HTTP(S) and FTP URLs in commit messages are automatically detected and open in the browser on click.
- **Commit SHA Navigation** — Commit SHA references in full commit messages are clickable and navigate directly to that commit in the history graph. Right-click shows options to copy the SHA or navigate to it.
- **Inline Code Formatting** — Backtick code spans (`` `like this` ``) in commit messages are rendered in monospace with a distinct background.
- **Hunk Staging** — Stage, unstage, or discard individual change hunks directly in the diff view (unified and side-by-side).
- **Stash Detail View** — Selecting a stash now shows its changes and a full diff preview in a 3-pane layout.
- **Syntax Highlighting in Diff** — TextMate-powered language-aware coloring in the diff view.
- **Commit Options** — Sign-Off, No-Verify, and Reset-Author checkboxes in the commit area.
- **History Improvements** — Ahead/behind indicators per commit, bisect good/bad markers, show/hide tags toggle, scroll-to-top button, loading indicator, and empty state tips.
- **Layout Switcher** — History view now supports horizontal (side-by-side) and vertical (top/bottom) layout.
- **Keyboard Shortcuts** — Ctrl+Shift+Enter (auto-stage + commit), Ctrl+F (search), Ctrl+O (open file).
- **Branch Descriptions** — Branch descriptions (via `git branch --edit-description`) now visible in tooltips.
- **Compact Folders** — Tree views in the working copy can now display compact/collapsed folder paths.

### Find Unused Blocks
- **Settings Dialog** — New gear icon opens a settings dialog. Configure which item types to include (Blocks, DBs, UDTs, Tags), toggle export reuse, and define exclusion patterns with wildcards (e.g. `FB_Test*;DB_Temp*`). Settings persist across restarts.
- **Compile + ExclusiveAccess** — Analysis now compiles the PLC first and runs snapshots + export inside ExclusiveAccess for data consistency and a native TIA Portal progress dialog.
- **PLC Selector** — Dropdown to choose which PLC to analyze. Exports go to PLC-specific subfolders, so multi-PLC projects don&apos;t conflict.
- **Project Save after Deletion** — TIA Portal project is automatically saved after deleting unused items.
- **Deletion Progress** — Progress bar now shows per-item deletion progress instead of staying on &quot;Preparing&quot;.
- **Deletion Log** — Timestamped log file written to working directory after each deletion with success/failure per item.

### Import
- **Protected Block Options** — Import Selected and Import All now respect per-block AllowCodeUpdates and AllowAttributeUpdates settings from protection profiles. Protected blocks with AllowCodeUpdates can have their SCL code updated; protected OBs with AllowAttributeUpdates get CyclicTime/PhaseOffset updates via SetAttribute.
- **SCL Folder Placement** — New blocks imported via SCL in Import Selected now land in the correct TIA Portal folder matching the disk structure, instead of always going to root &quot;Program blocks&quot; (V17+).

### Explorer
- **Split View** — Split editors horizontally or vertically, drag tabs between groups, dock and pin panels
- **Auto-Completion** — IntelliSense for SCL: type 2+ characters to see keywords, data types, built-in functions, and document words. Works for all file types in the File Explorer.
- **Code Folding** — Collapse and expand REGION, IF/FOR/WHILE blocks, VAR sections, and FUNCTION_BLOCK declarations. Brace-based folding for C#, JSON, and other languages.
- **Built-in Search** — Ctrl+F opens find and replace with regex, match case, and whole word support (replaces the old search toolbar).
- **SCL Snippets** — Type `if`, `for`, `while`, `case`, `fb`, `fc`, or `region` and press Tab to insert code templates with editable placeholders.
- **Theme Switching** — Editor colors now automatically adapt when switching between Dark and Light themes.
- **Current Line Highlight** — Visual indicator for the active cursor line.
- **Column Rulers** — Vertical guidelines at 80 and 120 characters.

### MCP Tools
- **Tool Consolidation** — Reduced from 81 to 22 MCP tools with multi-category support and dynamic permissions. Less token usage, better AI tool selection.

### Bug Fixes
- Fixed Cancel button not working for Export, Import, and Find Unused operations — pressing Cancel now immediately stops the running operation
- Fixed Import All ignoring AllowCodeUpdates for protected blocks — SCL files were incorrectly filtered out even when code updates were allowed
- Fixed empty export folders created next to PLC folder instead of inside it when &quot;Create Source Folder&quot; was disabled
- Fixed sub-agents unable to send messages back to the main AI agent — inter-agent messaging now works bidirectionally
- Fixed instruction file @include not recognizing bare relative paths (e.g. `@docs/rules.md`)
- Fixed long tool descriptions overflowing UI tooltips</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
</item>
