<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>3.4.0</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/releases/download/v3.4.0/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_3.4.0.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-04-22</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### Welcome
- **Welcome tab** — interactive introduction with Get Started walkthrough on fresh install.

### Compare Panel
- **Redesigned diff editor** — Consolidated toolbar, cleaner change navigation, SCL syntax highlighting, and a streamlined set of actions (Edit, Save, Discard, Merge, Swap, Clear) alongside the built-in diff controls.
- **Context-lines collapse** — Unchanged stretches far from any edit are folded behind a hunk header; buttons increase or decrease how much context is shown, or expand the entire file in one click.
- **Working edit mode** — Toggle Edit to modify either side of the diff in place and save back to the file or PLC from the same toolbar.
- **Preview Diff works on first click** — No more &quot;cache not found&quot; error on fresh checkouts or new working directories; the baseline is built automatically on the first run.
- **Compare** — Block icons in the file list, matching the project tree.
- **Compare** — Symmetric right-side file list with its own show/hide toggle for inspecting the disk side alongside the TIA side.
- **Compare** — Color-coded change strip at the right edge of each file-list row for at-a-glance change classification.
- **Git** — Diff viewer in commit details and revision compare no longer shows unused Compare-panel buttons.

### AI Chat
- **Write Unit Tests** — now supports AWL/STL blocks in addition to SCL.

### Bug Fixes
- **AI Chat** — AWL→SCL conversion preserves the original block header and comments verbatim.
- **AI Chat** — Completed tool approvals collapse to a compact status line instead of keeping the full warning card on screen.
- **OPC UA** — Method-call, matrix-editor, and certificate-management dialogs show their full content without left-edge clipping.
- **Editor** — Empty split panes close automatically when their last tab is closed.
- **Compare** — Preview Diff surfaces export failures in the status bar instead of leaving the editor blank.
- **Compare** — Each block appears only once in the Preview Diff file list regardless of export format.</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
    <size>253977480</size>
    <sha256>1C51C1ED560791986ACC37F4685BD3A9BB41233EDE26BE259AB599F96967EF8A</sha256>
</item>
