<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>3.5.0</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/releases/download/v3.5.0/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_3.5.0.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-04-24</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### AI Chat
- **AI Chat** — Importing or generating TIA blocks now always asks for explicit confirmation before changes are applied.
- **AI Chat** — Removing or deleting unit tests now always asks for explicit confirmation before changes are applied.
- **Azure OpenAI** — Chat-completions deployments now respect the configured request timeout on long-running calls.
- **Reasoning effort** — Pick per agent how hard the model thinks (Low / Medium / High) from the composer bar or Settings.
- **Provider settings tab** — New Providers section in AI Chat Settings shows GitHub Copilot sign-in status, enterprise domains in use, the reasoning-model policy state, and a catalog-refresh button. Placeholder cards for the other configured providers preview the upcoming Manage Language Models browser.
- **Manage Language Models window** — New cross-provider model browser behind the gear icon in the composer bar. Search by name or ID, filter by provider, see per-model Tool / Vision / Reasoning badges and the Copilot request multiplier, apply a model to the active agent in one click.
- **Manage Language Models window** — Claude models signed in via Anthropic OAuth now appear in the catalog alongside OpenAI, Google, and GitHub Copilot.
- **Manage Language Models window** — Reasoning, Vision, Tool, context-window and max-output badges fall back to the community model catalog when a provider&apos;s /v1/models response does not report them.
- **Copilot model policy badges** — The Manage Language Models window now shows per-model Enabled / Failed / Admin-managed status for GitHub Copilot rows, with a right-click retry for failed models.
- **Azure OpenAI — multiple deployments per agent** — Register additional Azure deployments with per-row Add / edit / Remove controls on an Azure agent and they all appear in Manage Language Models.

### Editor
- **Drag &amp; drop from the Project Explorer** — Drop one or several blocks or offline source files onto the code editor or the Welcome tab; each dropped item opens as its own editor tab.

### PLC Explorer
- **PLC Explorer sidebar** — Keep a list of your frequently-used PLCs in a dedicated workspace, see at a glance which ones are reachable, and double-click to open a connection tab with the IP and protocol already filled in.

### Unit Testing
- **Unit Testing** — workspace renamed from &quot;SCL Unit Testing&quot;.

### Bug Fixes
- **AI Chat** — Claude context window no longer reports 1 000 000 tokens when the 1M extended-context toggle is off; the composer bar shows the actual 200 000-token limit your plan uses.
- **Output panel** — Maximize now fills the workspace even while the Welcome tab is open.
- **Welcome tab** — Dropping a file from Windows Explorer or the File Tree onto the Welcome tab now opens it in the editor instead of being ignored.
- **Protection profiles** — Active profile stays applied after Import All.
- **Compare** — Dropping items on the right side now lists them on the right instead of defaulting to the left.
- **Compare** — Side-aware drops refresh the file list immediately, dedupe re-exports of the same block, and keep the header in sync with the clicked file.
- **Compare** — Diff backgrounds, highlights, and minimap now follow the active light/dark theme instead of staying dark.
- **Profiles bar** — Selected profile name is vertically centered, and the add-profile field is wide enough to show its full label.
- **Import / Delete errors** — Failed groups now show their real path, and errors are surfaced in the in-app log as well as the log file.
- **File tree icons** — User-defined data types are recognised and shown with their own icon; non-TIA files no longer borrow block icons.
- **Canvas** — Agent-drawn Canvas2D graphics stay visible after the agent finishes: the placeholder message is cleared on first draw, and drawings are re-painted when the Canvas panel is resized.
- **Canvas** — Mouse clicks on agent-drawn Canvas2D shapes now reach the agent&apos;s event handlers; A2UI widgets keep receiving clicks unchanged.</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
    <size>254366712</size>
    <sha256>8A5CB48DE0CF871D91871523A54E990B40273D7E453E3FE284D1D7BED481788F</sha256>
</item>
