<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>3.5.2</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/releases/download/v3.5.2/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_3.5.2.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-04-29</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### AI Chat
- **AI Chat** — Claude models on GitHub Copilot no longer time out during long reasoning calls.
- **AI Chat** — Stream timeouts log the system proxy used for the failing endpoint.
- **AI Chat** — AWL→SCL conversion catches self-IDB access, Bool bit-slices, and INT→DInt promotion before emitting SCL.
- **AI Chat** — Ctrl+B sends blocking sub-agents to background; main-session detach is no longer offered.
- **AI Chat** — File system tool can access the open TIA project&apos;s directory and any folders added in Settings → Workspace; out-of-scope paths trigger an allow/deny prompt.
- **AI Chat** — File system tool keeps protected app files (vault, license, chat data, settings) off-limits even inside allow-listed folders.
- **AI Chat** — Canvas snapshot tool now captures the visible canvas.
- **AI Chat** — MCP servers with arbitrary display names (spaces, punctuation, accents) now start successfully.
- **AI Chat** — Edit MCP Server dialog opens above the AI Chat Settings window.
- **AI Chat** — MCP server commands at install paths containing parentheses (e.g. `C:\Program Files (x86)\…`) are now accepted.

### PLC Online
- **OPC UA** — Failed writes surface a localized reason (read-only / permission denied / type mismatch / out of range / generic) inline below the watch row, with the row staying in edit mode for retry.
- **OPC UA** — Failed struct writes show a banner above the Struct Fields panel with the same localized reason.
- **OPC UA** — Writes with no server result now report it instead of silently appearing to succeed.
- **OPC UA** — Pressing Write on the struct editor with no field changes shows a &quot;No changes to write&quot; banner; starting a new edit clears it.
- **OPC UA** — Watch-table polls, struct edits and writes survive transient server-side blips instead of failing outright.

### Git
- **Git** — Partial stage / unstage / discard now works on diff lines with non-UTF8 text.
- **Git** — Create Branch popup hides the Local Changes radio when the working tree is clean.

### Editor
- **Editor** — Header `Language:` shows the real language for TIA Portal blocks (SCL/STL/LAD/FBD) and opened files (C#, Python, Markdown, TypeScript, …) instead of always SCL or XML.

### Unit Testing
- **Unit Testing** — Test suite files keep special characters (°, &lt;, +, accents) intact.
- **Unit Testing** — Test Explorer picks up new suites without a project reload.
- **Unit Testing** — New Suite button stays disabled until a block is selected.
- **Unit Testing** — Suite names with invalid characters or path-traversal sequences are rejected at every entry point.
- **Unit Testing** — Connection Settings persist when applied, and save errors appear in the status bar.
- **Unit Testing** — New Suite opens with a ready-to-edit example test case; the user manual now includes a full schema reference.
- **Unit Testing** — Example test case uses safe defaults (Bool inputs default to `false`) so a one-click Run cannot accidentally activate outputs on real hardware; user manual gains a safety callout.
- **Unit Testing** — Visual editor lets you author test cases through a form (Name / Description / Cycles / Tags / Priority + grids for Inputs, Assertions, Watch) instead of an empty page.
- **Unit Testing** — Multi-phase test steps — author write/wait/assert sequences in a single case for timing-dependent scenarios (reset → wait → start → wait → check) instead of chaining brittle multi-case state.
- **Unit Testing** — PLCSim Advanced saved-instances list scrolls within its own panel instead of overlapping the active-instances row.
- **AI Chat** — AI-generated unit tests are deterministic instead of depending on the PLC&apos;s current state.
- **AI Chat** — Unit-test agent uses the test case&apos;s watch array directly instead of searching for non-existent watch / monitor / subscribe / trace tools.
- **AI Chat** — Boundary-values tool no longer fails for blocks with Real/LReal inputs.

### Screen Editor
- **Screen Editor** — Item borders now render correctly.

### Trace
- **Trace** — Signal-color swatches render correctly when adding a computed signal.
- **Trace** — Signal picker now enables Add for OPC UA variables whose data type is a numeric NodeId (e.g. `i=1`, `i=4`).</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
    <size>255334760</size>
    <sha256>EF76644FD701263A6A9E2A76503E1D8BCAF54867468B8ED8FBAB6D6A5247F33E</sha256>
</item>
