<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>3.5.3</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/releases/download/v3.5.3/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_3.5.3.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-04-30</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### Quick Open
- **Quick Open** — new title-bar search bar (Ctrl+Shift+P, or click) jumps to commands, symbols, files, Git branches, help and lines across the whole app.

### Git
- **Git** — Diff editor in commit details and revision compare now spans the full pane width instead of leaving empty margins on both sides.

### Unit Testing
- **Unit Testing** — Run-History dock-tool lists every persisted test run with status, counts, suite, PLC, hostname and TIA version, with one-click jump back to the detailed Results view.
- **Unit Testing** — New &quot;Real PLC&quot; preparation mode runs tests directly against live S7 hardware via S7 Native, with an explicit acknowledgement dialog before the first write.
- **Unit Testing** — S7 transport label renamed to &quot;S7 Native&quot; across the Connection Settings dialog to match the PLC Online tab.
- **Unit Testing** — Tests against password-protected S7-1500 CPUs now authenticate with the credentials saved in the Connection Settings dialog instead of connecting anonymously.
- **Unit Testing** — Suite validation rejects malformed S7 IP addresses and overlong user names earlier with a clearer error.
- **Unit Testing** — JSON editor flags schema violations alongside JSON parse errors instead of only catching syntax issues.
- **Unit Testing** — Compare-Runs dock-tool diffs two runs with summary pills, filter bar (regressions / fixed / new / removed) and color-coded case rows; launched from Run-History &quot;Compare with…&quot; via a run-picker dialog.

### AI Chat
- **AI Chat** — MCP OAuth display name now refreshes after token rotation instead of showing the stale login-time name.
- **Scheduled Tasks** — schedule autonomous AI agent runs on a cron expression.

### PLC Online
- **OPC UA** — History chart now reads aggregate values (Average, Minimum, Maximum, Count, Total) over a configurable processing interval instead of only raw samples.
- **OPC UA** — Matrix editor warns when cells changed on the server while you were editing, with Overwrite or Reload choice instead of silently overwriting.

### Password Vault
- **Password Vault** — Newly created vault files now reload correctly after closing and reopening the app.
- **Password Vault** — Corrupted or incomplete vault files now show &quot;vault file is corrupted&quot; instead of repeated &quot;wrong master password&quot; prompts.
- **Password Vault** — All vault error messages are now fully translated.
- **Password Vault** — When the vault file is modified by another tool while the app has it open, the next save shows a clear &quot;vault file changed on disk&quot; warning instead of silently overwriting the external change.
- **Tool Approvals** — A corrupted approval file is preserved as a timestamped backup for inspection instead of being silently overwritten when you grant the next tool.</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
    <size>255780200</size>
    <sha256>00B054A88D0D4745B617994F4E0F1E8077AD52C3DB77CFF184D0D67CF8946136</sha256>
</item>
