<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>4.0.1</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/releases/download/v4.0.1/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_4.0.1.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-05-20</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### Editor
- **Editor** — Footer language dropdown lists SCL and AWL on top under a &quot;TIA Portal Languages&quot; group, followed by the alphabetical list of every other supported syntax; the chosen language re-highlights the current tab immediately.
- **Editor** — AWL files render with dedicated Statement-List syntax highlighting (mnemonics, comparison and arithmetic operators, comments and quoted DB names) instead of falling back to the SCL grammar.

### AI Chat
- **GitHub Copilot** — Commit-message generation and chat are ready on the first attempt after app start.
- **AI Chat Settings** — Sub-section selection in the left tree works reliably.

### TIA Portal
- **Archive Project** — Save the active TIA Portal project as an archive file with the matching `.zapXX` extension so the archive opens directly in TIA Portal; the Save Archive dialog accepts a configurable filename suffix and an optional timestamp (Settings → Files &amp; Folders → Archive Naming), the timestamp format follows the General/Git date-format setting and is shown in a live preview, and dialog title plus status messages follow the selected interface language.

### PLC Online
- **OPC UA** — Cancel button on stuck connection attempts; unreachable servers fail in 30 seconds; background type loading lets large controllers browse immediately after connect.

### Workspace
- **Workspace** — Bottom panel remembers its collapsed and maximized state across application restarts.</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
    <size>337506248</size>
    <sha256>98C60AFEC871823F663CF40F96E913EE5BB5975FB9168452943F294540B13847</sha256>
</item>
