<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>4.0.3</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/releases/download/v4.0.3/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_4.0.3.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpennessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-05-27</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### Editor
- **Editor** — UDT-typed members in the Interface view now expand to show their structure.
- **SCL Editor** — Syntax and basic semantic problems appear in the Problems panel and as in-editor markers while you edit, for blocks opened from the project and standalone SCL files.

### Find Unused
- **Find Unused** — Now asks you to fix compile errors before analyzing, so results stay accurate.
- **Find Unused** — Always analyzes a fresh export now, so results always reflect the current project.

### Protection
- **Protection** — Protecting or unprotecting a folder now applies only to the device you select.
- **Protection** — After this update, re-apply protection once in projects and profiles that already had it set.

### Licensing
- **Licensing** — Removed trial-transfer prompts and notifications.

### Unit Testing
- **Unit Testing** — Run your SCL tests on a build server and get JUnit and branded HTML reports.
- **Unit Testing** — Test results show the measured value next to each expected value.
- **Unit Testing** — Connection settings offer an explicit S7 Native transport with a dedicated option for running against a real PLC.
- **Unit Testing** — The Manage button in connection settings opens the simulation instances view.
- **Unit Testing** — Generate a ready-to-commit CI/CD pipeline for your tests from inside the app, run on demand.
- **Unit Testing** — Generated CI/CD pipelines can now target your own self-hosted test runner.

### Application Shell
- **Project Explorer** — The reload button stays clickable after a project finishes loading.
- **Settings** — The Additional S7DCL Export and Fingerprint Cache entries in the category tree now show their icons.
- **Theming** — Empty checkboxes are clearer and the bottom panel divider is slimmer.</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
    <size>578309592</size>
    <sha256>98C7C4BAD5F51F3F80B3DD8E297579A83AB82C9CAA4C7E1F86F52C6C845B1CF0</sha256>
</item>
