<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<item>
    <version>3.2.0</version>
    <url>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpenessManager/releases/download/v3.2.0/TiaOpennessManager_Setup_3.2.0.exe</url>
    <changelog>https://github.com/StaniB88/TIAOpenessManager/blob/main/CHANGELOG.md</changelog>
    <release_date>2026-04-14</release_date>
    <body>## What&apos;s Changed

### SCL Unit Testing (BETA)
- **New feature** — Integrated unit test framework for SCL blocks. Write, run and evaluate tests against a live PLCSIM Advanced instance without leaving the app. Requires PLCSIM Advanced V3.0+ (separate Siemens license)
- **Test Explorer** — Tree of all test suites in the project&apos;s `.tia-tests/` folder with live status icons (Pass / Fail / Error / Skipped). The explorer auto-detects new, deleted and modified suite files
- **Run tests** — Run Suite, Run Test (single case), Run All, Run Selected from the Test Explorer context menu or the Run button. Live progress streams through phase updates and per-test-case status icons while the run is active
- **Persistent results** — Test results are saved locally and reappear automatically when you reopen the app
- **Search and filter** — Text filter across suite and test case names, plus a &quot;Failed only&quot; toggle that hides all passing suites
- **Test suite editor** — Create test suites with the JSON, Visual or SCL editor modes. Block interface, boundary values and dependencies are extracted from the TIA project with a single click
- **Results panel** — Per-test-case detail grid with Variable, Operator, Expected, Actual and Pass/Fail markers for every assertion
- **Rename and delete suites** — Right-click a test suite in the Test Explorer to rename or delete it. Deleting also clears the run history for that suite
- **Manage test cases** — Right-click a test case to edit its name and description, duplicate it, delete it, or move it up and down in the list
- **PLCSIM Settings dialog** — New toolbar button opens a dialog for per-suite PLCSIM configuration (instance name, IP address, cycle wait time, auto-connect), with an option to save the values as defaults for new suites
- **Failed variable highlighting** — When a test case fails, the affected variable is underlined in red directly in the generated SCL code, with the error message shown on hover
- **Click-to-navigate from results** — Double-clicking a test case in the Results panel jumps to the corresponding position in the suite editor
- **Variable name check before running** — Before a run starts, the manager warns about variable names in the suite that don&apos;t exactly match the block interface, including case differences. You can still run the suite after acknowledging the warning
- **Auto-reload of open suites** — Suite files are now automatically reloaded in the editor when they&apos;re modified externally, unless there are unsaved local changes

### AI Chat
- **Removed Terminal Mode from AI Chat**
- **More accurate AI responses** — Built-in agents and skills have been refined to give more reliable results when working with TIA Portal projects
- **Automatic context window sizes** — AI Chat now picks the right context window for every supported model, including brand-new models released after your app version. No more guessing or waiting for an app update when a new model launches
- **Context window override** — Advanced agent settings have a new &quot;Context Window Override&quot; field for setting a custom context window per agent, plus an &quot;Enable 1M context (Anthropic Beta)&quot; toggle that opts Anthropic models into the 1M-token context beta
- **Live sub-agent info in the chat bubble** — Dispatched sub-agents now show their name, current activity, tool count, token usage, elapsed time and a stop button directly in the chat bubble, right where the agent was started. No more jumping between chat and a separate panel to check progress
- **Jump-back button when sub-agents run off-screen** — If you scroll up while a sub-agent is still working, a small pill at the bottom of the chat shows how many agents are running and jumps you back to the first running one when clicked
- **Mouse wheel unsticks auto-scroll reliably** — Scrolling up with the mouse wheel during a streaming response now always stops the chat from auto-scrolling back to the bottom

### Help &amp; Support
- **Report Issue from inside the app** — New Help → Report Issue entry. Pick Bug Report or Feature Request, fill in a title and description, and the app opens GitHub in your browser with the issue pre-filled. System information (app version, OS, TIA Portal version, language) is attached automatically so you don&apos;t have to look it up. Bug reports can optionally include recent log lines to help with diagnosis

### Code Editor
- **Syntax Highlighting Persistence** — Fixed syntax highlighting disappearing when switching between editor tabs or rapidly opening blocks. Highlighting now survives tab switches reliably
- **AI inline edits on SCL with special characters** — Fixed AI inline edits failing to match code containing characters like `&lt;`, `&gt;`, `+`, `°`, and quotes. AI edits now work reliably on all SCL code regardless of formatting quirks

### Import / Export
- **Auto-Compile before Export Selected** — Pressing &quot;Export Selected&quot; now automatically compiles the PLC before exporting, so blocks are always up-to-date. If compilation fails, the export continues and skips any still-inconsistent blocks

### Bug Fixes
- Fixed GitHub Copilot chat returning &quot;Misdirected Request&quot; errors for Business and Enterprise Copilot accounts — chat requests are now sent to the account&apos;s correct host
- Fixed Project Explorer Disconnect leaving the &quot;Protect: N&quot; badge and the selected protection profile visible after closing the project — both now clear together with the project tree
- Fixed &quot;Clear Protection&quot; leaving the code and attribute toggles visible on blocks — clearing the protection selection now also resets the protection mark and options
- Fixed Project Explorer still showing the project tree after disconnecting while a search filter was active
- Fixed AI Chat responses sometimes appearing with missing code blocks at the end of a message
- Fixed Import/Export settings opened from the View menu showing default values instead of your saved settings, and changes made there being silently discarded
- Fixed MCP Server &quot;Allow Write Operations&quot; toggle resetting to off on every app restart — the setting is now remembered
- Fixed AI Chat Memory settings always showing &quot;0 memories&quot; — the panel now displays memories for the active agent
- Fixed AI Chat agent URLs being silently reset on every app start and whenever the Settings dialog was opened or closed — your configured endpoints are now stable across sessions
- Fixed Git Preferences: date format, 24-hour clock, and &quot;Ignore CR at EOL&quot; settings had no effect — changes are now applied immediately
- Fixed Git Preferences: &quot;Max History Commits&quot; slider had no effect — history now respects the configured limit
- Fixed Git Preferences: &quot;Open in Terminal&quot; always opened cmd.exe instead of the shell configured in Integration settings
- Fixed Git Preferences showing empty Install Path and version 0.0.0 after startup
- Fixed crash when selecting certain protection profiles from the dropdown</body>
    <mandatory>false</mandatory>
    <size>251522288</size>
    <sha256>004618DFD2F3F2B1C1444DB03061222E7CD015C5D3AA32B07FADBB12DCC51C38</sha256>
</item>
